Guide to the Charles Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PRINTED MATERIAL, 1895, 1915-(1919)-1963; Series V; 4.5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  - Pamphlets
    - Re: Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes, Kingdom of (Box 80, Folder 97-100)
    - Re: Silesia (Box 80, Folder 101)
    - Re: The Slovenes (Box 80, Folder 102)
    - Re: Steiermark (Box 80, Folder 103)
    - Re: Styria (Box 80, Folder 104)
    - Re: Teschen-Silesia (Box 80, Folder 105)
    - Re: Trieste (Box 80, Folder 106)
    - Re: The Tyrol (Box 81, Folder 107)
    - Re: The Ukraine (Box 81, Folder 108)
    - Re: Vienna: Reports of Financial Institutions (Box 81, Folder 109-110)
    - "War Loans and War Services" (Box 81, Folder 111)
    - Re: Yugoslavia (Box 81, Folder 112)
    - Miscellaneous, 1917-1919, 1922-1924, 1926-1932, undated (Box 81, Folder 113-114a)
  - Authors' Complimentary Copies
    - Altschul, Charles. Article reprint, 1926 (Box 82, Folder 115)
    - Binkley, Robert C. Article reprints, 1929, 1931 (Box 82, Folder 115a)
    - Edwards, Sir Goronwy. "Presidential Address: The Historical Study of the Welsh Lawbooks," Transactions of the Royal Historical Society (1962), pp. 141-155. (Box 82, Folder 115b)
    - Edwards, Sir Goronwy. "Presidential Address: The Royal Household and the Welsh Lawbooks," Transactions of the Royal Historical Society (1963), pp. 163-176. (Box 82, Folder 116)
    - Fairchild, Fred Rogers. Article reprint, 1922 (Box 82, Folder 116a)
    - Latimer, Hugh. Naval Disarmament: A Brief Record from the Washington Conference to Date (1930). (Box 82, Folder 116b)
    - Lichnowsky, Prince. My Mission to London: 1912-1914 (1916). (Box 82, Folder 117)
    - Lutz, Ralph H. Article reprint, 1930 (Box 82, Folder 117a)
    - Miles, Walter R. Article reprint, 1935 (Box 82, Folder 117b)
    - Miller, David Hunter. Problems of Disarmament: Comments on the German Questionnaire (1926). (Box 82, Folder 117c)
    - Rahder, Johannes. "An Etymological Vocabulary of Chinese, Japanese, Korean, and Ainu," Journal of Asiatic Studies (1959), pp. 317-406. (Box 82, Folder 118)
    - Rahder, Johannes. "An Etymological Vocabulary of Chinese, Japanese, Korean, and Ainu, Part II," Journal of Asiatic Studies (1959), pp.307-371. (Box 82, Folder 119)
    - Rahder, Johannes. "An Etymological Vocabulary of Chinese, Japanese, Korean and Ainu, Part IV," Journal of Asiatic Studies (1960). (Box 82a, Folder 120)
    - Rahder, Johannes. "An Etymological Vocabulary of Chinese, Japanese, Korean, and Ainu, Part V," Journal of Asiatic Studies (1962). (Box 82a, Folder 121)
    - Schmitt, Bernadotte. Article reprints, 1924, 1926, 1930, 1936 (Box 82a, Folder 122)
    - Sheldon, Winthrop Dudley. The United States and the Disarmament Conference (1926) (Box 82a, Folder 122a)
    - Strout, Cushing. Article reprint, 1955 (Box 82a, Folder 123)
    - Van der Essen, Leon. Article reprints, 1923-1924 (Box 82a, Folder 123a)
    - Yuhasz, Michael Sr. Wilson's Principles in Czechoslovak Practice: The Situation of the Carpatho-Russian People Under the Czech Yoke (1929) (Box 82a, Folder 123b)
- HOUSE COLLECTION/ADMINISTRATION, 1928-(1940-1959)-1964; Series VI; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  General (the first four sections are contained in one box) This section consists of the record book listing the readers who used the House Collection 1949-1956, miscellaneous information concerning the administration and care of a manuscript collection, Reports to the Librarian of various years, and communications with reference librarians.
  Financial Records
  This section consists of records of the House Fund for the years 1924-1964 and insurance information for the years 1948-1949. The material is arranged chronologically.
  Personnel
  This section contains material relating to Associate Curator Russell Pruden for the years 1936-1947, followed by material concerning bursary aides who worked in the House Collection 1940-1957.
  Applications
  This section contains copies of the applications completed by researchers who desired access to the papers in the House Collection. The applications are arranged alphabetically.
  Correspondence (3 boxes)
  This section contains Seymour's correspondence as curator of the House Collection. The material is arranged alphabetically. Single letters are filed under the first letter of the correspondent's last name (e.g., A - C: miscellaneous). More extensive correspondence is filed under the full name of the person.
  - General
    - Record book of those who used the House Collection, 1949-1956 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Administration and care of a manuscript collection, 1928, 1930-1933, 1939-1941, 1943-1944, 1952, undated (Box 83, Folder 2-3)
    - Reports to the Librarian, 1951-1954, 1956-1957 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Reference Librarians: miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Financial Records
    - House Fund, 1924, 1929-1933, 1935-1937, 1943, 1946-1964, undated (Box 83, Folder 6-12)
    - Insurance information, 1948-1949 (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Personnel
    - Associate Curator - Russell Pruden, 1936-1947 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Bursary Aides, 1940, 1948, 1950-1957 (Box 83, Folder 15-16)
  - Applications
    - A - D (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - E - H (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - J - O (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - P - W (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence
    - A - C: miscellaneous (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Anderson, Allen G., 1931-1932 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Auchincloss, Edward H., 1949-1950 (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Bacon, Eugene H., 1950 (Box 84, Folder 24)
    - Bailey, Thomas A., 1940, 1942-1944, 1953, 1956-1957 (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - Barkley, M., 1955-1956 (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - Barrett, Mary X. (Mrs. John W.), 1942 (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - Beaverbrook, Baron (Sir William Maxwell Aitken), 1955, 1957 (Box 84, Folder 28)
    - Beers, Burton F., 1957 (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - Bender, Robert A., 1950 (Box 84, Folder 30)
    - Binkley, Robert C., 1930 (Box 84, Folder 31)
    - Birdsall, Paul, 1939-1941 (Box 84, Folder 32)
    - Birnbaum, Karl E., 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 84, Folder 33)
    - Blaisdell, Doris A., 1948 (Box 84, Folder 33a)
    - Blum, John M., 1937, 1947-1948, 1950 (Box 84, Folder 34)
    - Buehrig, Edward H., 1956 (Box 84, Folder 34a)
    - Bunyan, James, 1936 (Box 84, Folder 35)
    - Burlingame, Roger, 1943 (Box 84, Folder 36)
    - Calcott, W. H., 1939, 1942 (Box 84, Folder 37)
    - Coit, Margaret L., 1952 (Box 84, Folder 38)
    - Coggleshell, Reginald, 1936, 1938-1939 (Box 84, Folder 39)
    - Conklin, Groff, 1944 (Box 84, Folder 40)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1944-1945 (Box 84, Folder 41)
    - Cox, Frederick J., 1947 (Box 84, Folder 42)
    - Curry, Roy Watson, 1951, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 43)
    - D: miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 44)
    - Darling, Arthur, 1952, 1954 (Box 84, Folder 45)
    - Davenport, Marcia, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 46)
    - David, William M., Jr., 1951-1952 (Box 84, Folder 47)
    - Davidonis, Anthony C., 1942 (Box 84, Folder 48)
    - E - G: miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 49)
    - Epstein, Harold, 1931 (Box 84, Folder 50)
    - Finnegan, Edward H., 1944 (Box 84, Folder 51)
    - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1944 (Box 84, Folder 52)
    - Friedel, Frank, 1951, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 53)
    - Gasser, Albert, 1949-1950 (Box 84, Folder 54)
    - George, Alexander L. and Juliette, 1951, 1956 May - 1957 (Box 84, Folder 55-56)
    - Gerson, Louis L., 1949-1952, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 57)
    - H - K: miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 58)
    - Harbaugh, William H., 1952 (Box 84, Folder 59)
    - Harmsworth, Geoffrey, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 60)
    - Haworth, Helen E., 1954 (Box 84, Folder 61)
    - Hooker, Richard, 1931 (Box 84, Folder 62)
    - Hosteler, Joseph C., 1941 (Box 85, Folder 63)
    - Howard, Harry N., 1941 (Box 85, Folder 64)
    - Hulick, Charles E., Jr., 1938, undated (Box 85, Folder 65)
    - Jamison, Alden, 1944 (Box 85, Folder 66)
    - Johnson, Evans C., 1951 (Box 85, Folder 67)
    - Kedourie, E. A., 1951-1952 (Box 85, Folder 68)
    - Keller, Pierre, 1951-1952 (Box 85, Folder 69)
    - Kennan, George F., 1955, 1959 (Box 85, Folder 70)
    - Klachko, Mary, 1956-1957 (Box 85, Folder 71)
    - Knox, Grace, 1942 (Box 85, Folder 72)
    - Kuehl, Warren F., 1952 (Box 85, Folder 73)
    - Kusielewicz, Eugene, 1954-1955 (Box 85, Folder 74)
    - Lauter, Beatrice, 1954-1956, 1958-1959 (Box 85, Folder 75)
    - Lee, Armistead, 1941 (Box 85, Folder 76)
    - Link, Arthur, 1942, 1944, 1946, 1949 (Box 85, Folder 77-78)
    - Lowry, Philip, 1940, 1946-1947 (Box 85, Folder 79)
    - L - M: miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 80)
    - McEnerney, Edward B., 1946-1947 (Box 85, Folder 81)
    - Malzahn, Richard L., 1955 (Box 85, Folder 82)
    - Mamatey, Victor S., 1952, 1957 (Box 85, Folder 83)
    - Mangano, Philip A., 1942 (Box 85, Folder 84)
    - Mantoux, Etienne, 1942 (Box 85, Folder 85)
    - Marder, Arthur J., 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 85, Folder 86)
    - Marlowe, Elizabeth, 1947 (Box 85, Folder 87)
    - May, Ernest R., 1951, 1955 (Box 85, Folder 88)
    - Muther, Jeannette E., 1950 (Box 85, Folder 89)
    - N - Y: miscellaneous (Box 85, Folder 90)
    - Nelson, Harold I., 1953, 1956 (Box 85, Folder 91)
    - Nichols, Jeanette P., 1942-1943 (Box 85, Folder 92)
    - Notter, Harley A., 1936 (Box 85, Folder 93)
    - Plunkett Foundation, 1946 (Box 85, Folder 94)
    - Richardson, Rupert N., 1956-1957, 1960-1961 (Box 85, Folder 95)
    - Robson, Albert N., 1951-1952 (Box 85, Folder 96)
    - Rollins, Alfred B., Jr., 1952 (Box 85, Folder 97)
    - Senn, Alfred, 1956 (Box 85, Folder 98)
    - Seymer, Lucy Buckler, 1957-1958 (Box 85, Folder 99)
    - Smith, Daniel M., 1952, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 100)
    - Snell, John L., 1952 November - 1956 (Box 86, Folder 101-102)
    - Sondermann, F. A., 1952-1953, 1957 (Box 86, Folder 103)
    - Sossomon, D. C., 1951 (Box 86, Folder 104)
    - Spector, Sherman D., 1948, 1956 (Box 86, Folder 105)
    - Spencer, Samuel R., Jr., 1950, 1952-1953 (Box 86, Folder 106)
    - State, United States Department of, 1940-1943 (Box 86, Folder 107-108)
    - Sweetser Arthur, 1955, 1957 (Box 86, Folder 108a)
    - Thiele, Grace M., 1952 (Box 86, Folder 109)
    - Thompson, John M., 1952-1953 (Box 86, Folder 110)
    - Tontarski, Richard E., 1951, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 111)
    - Ullman, Richard H., 1957 (Box 86, Folder 112)
    - Unterberger, Betty M., 1946, 1954 (Box 86, Folder 113)
    - Warth, Robert D., 1951 (Box 86, Folder 114)
    - Waters, Maurice, 1955-1956 (Box 86, Folder 115)
    - Willis, Edward F., 1945 (Box 86, Folder 116)
    - Wimer, Kurt, 1957-1958 (Box 86, Folder 117)
    - Yale, William, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 118)
- FOLIOS
  - Pamphlet: Bulgarians in their historical, ethnographical, and philosophical frontiers, 1919 (Box 87)
  - Book of letters presented to Charles Seymour on the occasion of his 75th birthday, January 1, 1960 (Box 88)
- VOLUMES
  - Conditions of Peace with Austria: French, English and Italian texts, 1919 (Box 89)
  - Reply of the Allied and Associated Powers to the Observations of the German Delegation on the Conditions of Peace, 1919 (Box 89)
  - Conditions of Peace 2 copies, 1919 (Box 90)